<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Evthron&#39;s blog en</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/society/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Evthron&#39;s blog en</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 02:34:20 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What I learn from economics</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/learn-from-economics/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 02:34:20 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/learn-from-economics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The society follows the principles of economics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one should do everything on their own, even if they could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a living, you just need to focus on one thing that only you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do one thing and do one thing well, like the Unix philosophy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ironically, that means as computer science student, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be learning even a little bit of economics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic predictions don&amp;rsquo;t work if we don&amp;rsquo;t consider factors besides money, such as  happiness and health. Since economists can only think in terms of money, we can convert everything we care about into prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think about it, you realise that pretty much everything can be converted into prices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, if no exchange could be done, this so-called &lt;em&gt;price&lt;/em&gt; is not very meaningful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make a lot of money, be a monopoly. Get a lisence, certificate, degree and anything that gives you the privilege to do the job so you can earn more than you should. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s great for you, but not so great for society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, if you are in free competition, you need to work hard to be as efficient as your competitors. It&amp;rsquo;s tough, but it&amp;rsquo;s better for the consumers. That&amp;rsquo;s capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
