<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Evthron&#39;s blog en</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/relationship/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Evthron&#39;s blog en</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:02:20 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/relationship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hard to ask for help</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tweet/hard-to-ask-for-help/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:02:20 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/tweet/hard-to-ask-for-help/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to ask for help. If you procrastinating until the last hour and realise you can&amp;rsquo;t solve the problem on time, the shame you feel when typing the text message to ask someone for help will makes you throw the phone away and panic alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we rely on the internet to answer every small question, we miss the chance to slowly build trust with others with these questions. It is very tempting to quickly obtain the knowledge without having to admit our ignorance. Is it really the cause? Only trust begets trust, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have to trust others when asking those easy questions, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether they could answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some extreme occasion, if I am really scared about the immediate danger, I will draw on everything in sight to save myself without a second thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I just don&amp;rsquo;t believe that I could get meaningful help. If I go ask about homework, instead of discussing the the answer together, they will finish the work alone and share their answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the filp side, if someone ask me for help, I can act immediately. I may feel annoyed sometimes, but I like the feeling to be prompted to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
