<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Evthron&#39;s blog en</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/relationship/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Evthron&#39;s blog en</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 13:53:18 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/relationship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Relationship management software</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/personal-relationship-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 13:53:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/personal-relationship-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://evthron.github.io/en/skill/right-sider/#keith-ferrazzi-tahl-raz---never-eat-alone--and-other-secrets-to-success-one-relationship-at-a-time&#34; &gt;Never Eat Alone&lt;/a&gt; suggests making a list to group people according to contact frequencies. Although the book recommends to stick to simple technology like pencil and paper, I still want a specialised software and I found monica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.monicahq.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monica (official site)&lt;/a&gt; calls itself a Persoal Relationship Management (PRM) software。On the other hand, Customer Relationship Management（CRM）is for people in the business sector to mangement their customer profiles (Never eat alone is a bit business-oriented at the outset). I think it beneficial to go the extra mile and put the same amount of effort to manage our own networks. Monica is open-source. You can run it on local server using the docker image they provide. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.monicahq.com/img/dashboard.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;example&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks promising but after trying it, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t enphasise enough on the features that I most needed, which is to remind me to keep in touch with people. Email notification is not going to work (and I don&amp;rsquo;t have a email server for now). The tagging and sorting functions are not very handy, while the handy event reminder panel can be replaced by other calendar software. It&amp;rsquo;s usable, but there should be some simpler tools that satisfy my needs. Maybe just pure text files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devs are working on a revised version called &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.monicahq.com/blog/chandler-is-in-beta&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chandler (monicahq.com)&lt;/a&gt;. See how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;docker is a tool for running websites. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit complicated to install that on  Windows. If you know nothing about this, it&amp;rsquo;s better to try their official service.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hard to ask for help</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/hard-to-ask-for-help/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:02:20 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/hard-to-ask-for-help/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to ask for help. If you procrastinating until the last hour and realise you can&amp;rsquo;t solve the problem on time, the shame you feel when typing the text message to ask someone for help will makes you throw the phone away and panic alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we rely on the internet to answer every small question, we miss the chance to slowly build trust with others with these questions. It is very tempting to quickly obtain the knowledge without having to admit our ignorance. Is it really the cause? Only trust begets trust, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have to trust others when asking those easy questions, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether they could answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some extreme occasion, if I am really scared about the immediate danger, I will draw on everything in sight to save myself without a second thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I just don&amp;rsquo;t believe that I could get meaningful help. If I go ask about homework, instead of discussing the the answer together, they will finish the work alone and share their answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the filp side, if someone ask me for help, I can act immediately. I may feel annoyed sometimes, but I like the feeling to be prompted to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
