<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Evthron&#39;s blog en</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/maths/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Evthron&#39;s blog en</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 03:07:53 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/maths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Higher order operation</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/posts/higher-order-operation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 03:07:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/posts/higher-order-operation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The reason why &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt; is natural is because the exponential function with base &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt; grows exactly at the rate of its own value. This is not a miracle. In fact, every exponential function grows proportionally to its own value, but not exactly. The number &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt; just happens to be the only one to achieve this, with the help of infinitely fine-tuned digits, just like how &lt;em&gt;π&lt;/em&gt; achieves the perfect radius-1 curvature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s very hard to imagine an exponential index that is not an integer. How on earth can an exponential index grow continuously? Things can only multiply by themselves once, twice, but not 1.5 times. We know that we can imagine it using roots, but this is not intuitive at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you remember, in primary school, we also took some time to understand what multiplying by a decimal number means. It means addition in fractions. Exponentiation follows this logic but one order higher—it means multiplication in roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes me think: can we extend this definition one order higher? How can we go beyond exponentiation? This is the fourth-order operation: tetration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tetration is a tower of powers. Each number becomes a tower of powers with a height the same as itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, 2 becomes 2 to the 2, and 3 becomes 3 to the 3 to the 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a special number in the realm of tetration, like &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;? Maybe the number whose &amp;ldquo;tetrational rate&amp;rdquo; (whatever that means) is equal to the value of the function itself. Forget about differentiation—maybe we can define a higher-order differentiation operation. To make this happen, we need to extend the definition of tetration, just like how we extended the definitions of multiplication and exponentiation to real numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we extend this definition to fractions? Unfortunately, this steps into the realm of unsolved math problems. There’s no generally accepted function to extend the definition of tetration to real numbers. If tetration is not a continuous function, there’s no hope in finding its derivative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, unlike exponentiation—which models many natural phenomena aptly—tetration is a completely useless operation because it grows so fast that we run out of atoms in the universe by the time we reach the number 4. Nothing in the universe can be modeled using tetration. No one even knows how to make an analogy to demonstrate its growth rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that exponentiate proportionally to its size—whatever that means.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>origami</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/origami/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 01:10:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/origami/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I received fliers on the street, I often felt the urge to make use of it. No, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean making paper planes, that no fun making paper planes. What about origami? (Though technically, making paper planes is origami) I remembered when I was in primary school, our maths teacher had taught us how to craft 3D shapes out of paper pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now as I am talking about maths, you may notice origami is very similar with constructing shapes using ruler and compass. Actually, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard origami is more powerful than ruler and compass because it can solve the unsolvable &amp;ldquo;trisect any angle&amp;rdquo; problem. When I was still holding the flier and walking, I started wondering what the basic mathematical operations of origami are. The first one could be folding a line in half, which forms the perpendicular bisector of the line. The other one might be folding an angle in half, which gave us the diagonal line. When all they do is to cut things in half, is cutting things in third even possible? I went straight to the library to find the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is stupidly simple: Just fold the line in half two times and cut out the extra segment. It&amp;rsquo;s like Columbus&amp;rsquo;s egg, my stubborn mind can&amp;rsquo;t solve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I still wanted a technical answer. Surprisingly, there weren&amp;rsquo;t many videos talking about the maths behind origami. Oddly, I could easily learn how to trisect angles by folding paper, but not for trisecting lines, which should be a much easier task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I tried that out myself. When using ruler and compass, the knack of that problem is to cast an already trisected line onto the new line using parallel lines. But how to make parallel lines in origami? Just remember that the perpendicular line of a perpendicular line is a parallel line. Let me share my experience: To get a more accurate result, the angle between the already trisected line and the new line should be small to make it easier to fold the perpendicular lines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
