<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Evthron&#39;s blog en</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/grumble/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Evthron&#39;s blog en</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 04:01:51 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://evthron.github.io/en/tags/grumble/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Bad mood holiday</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/bad-mood-holiday/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 04:01:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/bad-mood-holiday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate holiday. It gives me a fake sense of comfort that I could slack off. Time flies no matter what I do. I always get stuck in deep regret and really annoyed by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;This is such a tiny thing. I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be angry and waste any more time on this.&amp;rsquo; This meta emotion makes me feel angrier. What a vicious circle, until I can&amp;rsquo;t take this anymore and cried. After that, I could sit down and write this reflection very easily. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to admit, but emotion plays heavily of the tug-of-war between motivation and procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Update breakage</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/update-breakage/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:30:46 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/update-breakage/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t update the system when I am doing work&amp;hellip; what a classic mistake. The bookmark bar of Firefox became blank and the button layout is stirred up. I spent the whole night trying to open new profiles and imported all the setting twice but somehow it couldn&amp;rsquo;t fix the problem. I have no choice but to remove all the profiles and reinstall firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joppy updates and spilt its API into clientAPI and serverAPI. I have to change my import statement in my python script to make it work. I now understand why people fixate on old versions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Haircut</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/haircut/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 23:57:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/haircut/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The hairdresser grumbled that my demand was unclear, although I had been using the same vague words and the outcomes were somewhat consistent. How misfortunate. At least I learnt their lingo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Sticky menu</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/sticky-menu/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 02:03:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/sticky-menu/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just want to make a menu that sticks on the pages using CSS, how come this could be so difficult? Even ChatGPT gave me the wrong answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024/06/25 03:44
Problem Solved. The key is to make the max height of the panel be 100vh minus top padding minus bottom padding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Improved publishing workflow </title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/easier-publish/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 21:19:00 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/easier-publish/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2024/03/30 21:19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can generate blog post directly from joplin thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/marph91/joppy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;joppy&lt;/a&gt;, which is a python version of Joplin API. Finally I did something useful for myself using python. Old posts should not be just dead archives of past thoughts. I should review and improve them after some period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024/03/30 23:06&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could simply use Obsidian or VS Code to edit the files, why should I configure this mess? For the sake of open source? I&amp;rsquo;m tired&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024/05/28 12:22
I dived in to the source code of joppy, which is not complicated at all. It&amp;rsquo;s just making requests to joplin&amp;rsquo;s native API. Scrutinising other&amp;rsquo;s work is really the best way to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;05/01/2025 11:23
It&amp;rsquo;s fine to make a copy for long posts, but it&amp;rsquo;s clumsy to copy quick thoughts like tweet. Maybe I should improve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025/03/24 22:41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncthing proved too sluggish for syncing my Joplin notes—Android&amp;rsquo;s transfer throttling turned every load into a test of patience. The solution? A self-hosted Joplin server via Docker. Now, I can seamlessly edit my blog posts straight from my phone, without the wait.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Delusions</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/delusions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 20:20:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/delusions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If there are negative delusions that haunt my mind, there must also be positives delusions that push me forward. There&amp;rsquo;s no way that my personal imagination can&amp;rsquo;t beat the socially constructed one. I am a writer after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Winter</title>
        <link>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/winter/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://evthron.github.io/en/tweet/winter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is so cold. I thought it would be warmer since the sunlight was so bright last week as if it were August. Sunny days can&amp;rsquo;t go on forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
